Hey guys, this is a quick demo for
Codesmith. It's a multi-agent AI system
that takes a prompt and turns it into
tested, fixed, and documented code all by
itself. Right now, we'll install it from
scratch, run a prompt, and look at what
each agent does.
I'll be using a conda terminal to create
the environment and run the project. I
prefer this over global Python, which
keeps things clean. I'll be cloning
this directly into my desktop.
We'll just follow the instruction here to
create a virtual environment and install
all the dependencies required.
The installation process is
time-consuming, so I'll skip through this
part.
As you can see, the streamlit UI is up.
I'll pick Gemini as the back end. You can
use a local Allama model as well, but for
the demo, I'll stick to a cloud model.
I'll get an API key. I'm choosing a
fast model. The flash is fine for this. I
don't have a paid Open AI key for now,
and running smaller local models is
slower and they hallucinate more as the
tasks get complex.
Now let's give it a simple prompt for
now, which is to generate a Python
calculator program.
As it runs, you'll see each agent section
fill in.
The product manager defines acceptance
criteria, a strict IO contract, and test
cases. Those test cases drive all
verification.
The architect explains the structure,
like how input parsing works, how output
must be exact. Helps keep it
deterministic.
The developer just gives the full program
inside a single fenced code block. No
extra fluff.
The QA agent extracts the code and the
test cases list, runs each test through a
remote sandbox . It feeds
standard input, captures standard output,
and marks pass or fail. If a mismatch,
you'd see expected versus actual.
Fix and retest agent if triggered,
patches the code and reruns QA until
everything passes or the cap hits.
Documentation Agent generates concise
usage instructions plus a couple example
runs matching the IO contract.
Tools available for now include one to
extract the latest code block, one to
parse test cases, a remote execution
tool, Piston, that safely runs code in
many languages, a write file helper, and
a tiny Python REPL for internalreasoning.
So that's Codesmith. Natural language in,
tested, fixed, documented program out.
You can swap providers, OpenAI,
Anthropic, Gemini, or Local Alama.
Extend it by adding a provider adapter or
a new tool. Repo links in description.
Star it if it helps you. See you later.